Jon Jackson

Lowell, AR 72745 479-601-3157 jonjackson.webdesign@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanjackson25 | https://github.com/jonteal | https://jonjacksondev.netlify.app/

About Me

I am deeply passionate about bringing my willingness and ability to solve problems to an agile team working towards a common goal of bringing the maximum value to the customer in the most efficient manner possible. Before entering the world of tech, I worked in a fast-paced sales and marketing environment which I believe gave me an ability to see product development with a business-growth perspective and the ability to relate to customers. Additionally, I am an extremely active listener with experience in leadership, creativity, problem solving, and building projects from ideation to execution.

Summary

- Experienced in software design, responsive design, frontend engineering in large-scale applications that are used by millions of daily active users
- Over 1 year of professional software development experience
- 6+ software projects. 3 projects live

Technical Skills * limited experience

Languages | Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL*, Python*

Frameworks | ReactJS, Wordpress, ExpressJS, NextJS, Bootstrap, Handlebars*

Javascript | Lodash, Webpack*, NPM, Axios, jQuery*, Sequelize, Prettier, ESLint, MomentJS

CSS | SASS, TailwindCSS, Material UI

Request/Formats | AJAX, JSON, REST, GraphQL

Databases | MySQL*, PostgreSQL*, MongoDB, Sqlite*

Cloud Services | AWS*, Google Cloud - Firebase*

Platforms | Web, Microsoft Office

Dev Ops | Docker* , BitBucket*, Github, CircleCI*

Third Party Services | Stripe*

Other | Figma*, Miro, NodeJS, Redux, Contentful (CMS), Micro-frontends*

Recent Projects

Study Buddy | Sole Project Developer

October 2022 - Present

A MERN full stack application developed to provide a tool for studying for upcoming tests and exams. **Technologies**: MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, GraphQL

• Architect, designer, developer

Github: https://github.com/jonteal/studybuddy

Capstone Clothing | Sole Project Developer

September

2022

A simple E-Commerce frontend application with standard cart features and payment processing. **Technologies**: ReactJS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Firebase, SASS, Typescript, Styled Components, Stripe

• Developed during Udemy course covering the latest standards and practices in large-scale apps Github: https://github.com/jonteal/capstone-e-commerce

Ozark AirBnb | Sole Project Developer

August 2022 - Present

A simple front end website for a small business within the Airbnb industry.

Technologies | ReactJS

• Developed as a website for a company I am developing as a side business.

Github: https://github.com/jonteal/ozark-airbnb

Experience

CVS Health | Digital Software Development Engineer

June 2022 - Present

Frontend web developer for Aetna Health using React, Typescript, Contentful, Redux, Sagas, GraphQL, and AWS.

- Develop features used by millions of healthcare members every day
- Maintain and increase code unit testing coverage, regression and end-to-end UI testing via Playwright
- Integrate features with CMS-driven content with GraphQL for full multi-language translatability
- Demonstrate sprint progress and new feature development to team leadership and stakeholders
- Implement tooling and programmatic prevention of accessibility (a11y) defects
- Review and quality test all pull requests on my team prior to code merge

2U/edX | Full Stack Tutor & Grader

Mar 2022 - May 2022

Tutor and grader supporting students going through a 6-month full stack engineering program.

- Tutoring 8 students for 1 hour per week each to support their learning and comprehension of concepts ranging from basic HTML, CSS, Javascript, developing and consuming APIs, SQL and NoSQL database creation and management, React, Git/Github, and more.
- Grading the weekly assignments of students and offering written feedback, guidance, and support.

Education

2U / edX | University of Denver (DU), Denver, CO Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022

University of Arkansas

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Science, Marketing

Personal

Interests | Spending time with family, avid reader, technology, writing music, running, rock climbing **Goals** | Start a tech company, climb a 14,000 foot mountain, read a book a week, always be improving